快好了
Almost done.
给你
Here.
再有点牛排就好了
If only we had some cab'.
闺蜜之夜
Girls' night.
它们又狂躁起来了
Boys are getting restless again.
你还没告诉过我呢
You still haven't told me,
你在哪发现它们的
Where did you find them?
它们袭击你  还是你专门捕获它们
Did they attack? Did you hunt them down?
你认识它们吗
Or did you know them?
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
老天
Oh god.
你想谈这事吗
You want to talk about it?
好吧
Okay.
它们罪有应得
They deserved what they got.
它们生前也不是什么好人
They weren't human to begin with.
《行尸走肉》
-你去拿点五零口径机枪  -好的
- You, grab the .50. - You got it.
总督要带这么多枪吗
The Governor wants all this?
-他希望有更多选择  -他在哪
- He wants options. - Where is he now?
不在这
Not here.
-去多少人  -所有人
- How many are going out? - Everybody.
我以为他们达成协议了
I thought there was a deal on the table.
我相信这只是防备措施
I'm sure it's just a precaution,
展示我们的武力
a show of force.
米尔顿
Milton.
Milton!
有什么事吗
You need something?
那是什么
What is that?
我的工作室
It's my workshop.
那对伍德伯里毫无帮助
How does that help Woodbury?
你说什么
Excuse me?
这本该是一个新起点
This was supposed to be a new start,
新希望
a way out.
我们之前谈过的那些事呢
What about everything we talked about?
克服困难  重振文明
Beating this thing? Clawing our way back?
你和米琼恩的恩怨
Look, this business with Michonne,
我理解
I understand.
但是监狱里的那些人
But the people at the prison...
怎么了
What?
-我应该释怀吗  -是的
- I should move on? - Yes.
这一切结束之后  我会释怀的
Well, I will as soon as this is over.
-菲利普  -我问你
- Philip-- - Let me ask you something, huh?
你还相信行尸是有意识的对吗
Do you still believe the biters have some spark in them, huh?
知道他们自己是谁
Of who they were?
我认为是的
I think so.
那死的就是我女儿  不是吗
Then that was my daughter, wasn't it?
不管是不是佩妮
Whether that was Penny or not,
木已成舟
It's done.
不重要了
It doesn't matter.
对我来说  这才最重要
It's all that matters.
没有什么协议  菲利普想要米琼恩
There is no deal. Philip's asked for Michonne.
瑞克不会同意的
Rick would never agree to that.
不管他交不交出她
Whether he hands her over or not,
他都会把他们都杀光
he's gonna kill them all.
-我得阻止这一切  -我觉得你办不到
- I have to stop this. - I don't think you can.
走吧
Leave.
告诉监狱里的人赶紧离开
Tell the people at the prison to get out of there.
时间会冲淡他的仇恨
In time, he'll move on.
不
No.
我得杀了他
I have to kill him.
你接近不了他
You'll never get close to him.
他们会先开枪杀了你
They'll gun you down first.
他们对我没有防备
Only if they see me coming.
米尔顿  这太变态了
Milton, this is sick.
我不能袖手旁观
I can't just stand back and watch this.
你怎么还保护他
How can you still protect him?
他根本不在乎你
He doesn't give a shit about you.
在菲利普成为总督前我就认识他
I knew Philip before he became the governor.
他本性未变
That man still exists.
我不相信
I don't believe that.
好吧  假设你杀了总督
Okay, so you kill the governor.
然后你又被枪杀了  然后马丁内斯接管
Then you get shot and Martinez takes over.
然后怎样
What then?
杀了总督也救不了你的朋友
Killing the governor doesn't save your friends.
那我就得回去  提醒他们
Then I have to go back. Warn them.
你跟我一起走
And you're coming with me.
我不能离开伍德伯里
I can't leave Woodbury.
你真想参与这场屠杀吗
You really want to be a part of this?
监狱里我谁也不认识
I don't know anyone at the prison.
那又怎样  你认识莫尔  他就待得挺好
So what? You know Merle. He fit in.
你会没事的
You'll be fine.
不管你喜不喜欢  我属于这
Like it or not, I belong here.
如果你留下
Then if you stay,
就不能让别人看出你有异心
you can't keep looking the other way.
保重
Take care of yourself.
你有其它的武器吗
You got any other weapons?
你们还有子弹吗  你们还有什么
D'you have more rounds? What do you guys got?
安德莉亚
Andrea.
Andrea!
总督要收缴所有武器
Governor wants all weapons collected.
要给部队全副武装
Got to get the team geared up.
我觉得我武装起来更有用
I think I'm more helpful armed.
把你的武器和弹药都交出来
Hand over your piece and any ammo.
不要
No.
别犯傻
Let's not be stupid about this.
交出你的武器
Hand over your piece.
你有刀子吗
You got a knife?
你想要搜我的身吗
You want to frisk me?
我本该告诉你这一切的  对不起
I should have told you about all this. I'm sorry.
我只是
I just, uh--
我不想把你也搅合进来
I want to keep you separate from this.
安全  你懂吧
Safe. You understand?
是的
Yeah.
我只是想帮忙
I just want to help.
你可以帮忙  明天吧
Well, you can. Tomorrow.
我要你和我们一起去见瑞克
I want you with us when we go and meet Rick.
如果他轻举妄动  你可以劝他理智些
He tries anything, you can talk some sense into him.
轻举妄动
Tries anything?
你相信他们  我可不信
Well, you trust them, I don't.
了解
Understood.
我会去的
I'll be there.
这个行尸交给你
You take this one.
你应该多练习
You need the practice.
放轻松
Just relax.
你在旁边一直啰嗦  让我怎么放松
How am I gonna relax if you keep telling me to relax?
差太远了
Wasn't even close.
-要不你来  -我早练过了
- You want to do this? - I have been.
你在浪费弹药
You're wasting ammo.
打中了
Got him.
干得漂亮
Nice shot.
有一大波行尸正在向主墙进发
Hey, large pack of walkers was spotted heading for the main wall.
马丁内斯需要支援  我来守着这边
Martinez wants some help. I got this covered.
我们不能擅离岗哨
We're not supposed to leave this post.
问马丁内斯吧  我只是奉命行事
Ask Martinez. I'm just doing what I'm told.
你得把他带过来  我们得听他的命令
You got to bring him over. We need to hear it from him.
-你是在浪费时间  -你怎么不去帮忙
- You're wasting time. - Why can't you handle it?
你是个神枪手啊
You're supposed to be a good shot.
-你在干什么  -我必须从这里出去
- What are you doing? - Got to get out of here.
-没人离开  -求你了  我不想惹麻烦
- Nobody leaves. - Please, I don't want any trouble.
-到底是怎么回事  -别挡我的路
- What is this about? - Just get out of my way.
-松手  -放松
- Don't. - Relax.
没必要互相伤害
Nobody's got to get hurt here.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起  这个地方
I'm sorry, it's just this place is--
-我没办法待在这里  -为什么
- I can't stay here. - Why?
总督  他表里不一
The governor, he is not what he seems to be.
他跟我们挺坦诚的啊
He seems pretty straight up to me.
我之前也那么以为
That's what I thought, too.
但我告诉你  他干过很卑鄙的事情
But I'm telling you, he has done terrible things.
他还在计划着更坏的事情
He's planning worse.
我得赶紧离开这里  劝你们也快走
I've got to get out of here and you should, too.
你太累了  头脑不清
Look, you're rattled, exhausted.
把刀放下
Just put the knife down.
我要走了
I'm going.
好吧
Okay.
我们不应该放她走
We shouldn't have let her go.
我能怎么办  打死她吗
What do you want me to do, shoot her?
-你应该阻止她  -怎么阻止
- You should have stopped her. - Stop her how?
从背后开枪打死她吗
Shoot her in the back?
不  你们做的对
No, you did the right thing.
还好你们俩没受伤
Thank god neither of you were hurt.
我们守在墙上阻止行尸进入
We stand on that wall to stop biters,
而不是阻止人们出去
not keep people in.
这里不是某种集中营吧
This isn't a prison camp, is it?
当然不是  只是...
Of course not. It's just
她没能力照顾自己
she's in no shape to take care of herself.
我觉得她完全有能力
Seems pretty capable to me.
她在外面待了一整个冬天
She was out there all winter
独自一人
alone.
你能想象吗
Can you imagine?
你们两个人有彼此  以及朋友
Now, you two had each other or your friends.
而她身边只有行尸
She only had the biters.
我们带她回来帮助她
We brought her in and tried to help her,
但太晚了
but it was too late.
外面已经改变了她
She'd been out there too long.
她...  说什么了吗
Did she-- did she say anything?
-你指哪方面  -我不知道
- Like what? - I don't know.
比如是什么让她感到恐惧
Like what panicked her?
没有
No.
我希望这不会影响到我们
I hope this doesn't affect us.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我们听说她以前和监狱的人是一伙
Well, we heard she was with that prison group.
我希望没添什么麻烦
I hope I didn't complicate things.
不  不
No. No.
听着  这样吧
Um, look, I'll tell you what.
马丁内斯这儿需要点助手
Martinez here could use a hand with something.
如果你们不介意的话就帮帮他
If you wouldn't mind helping him out,
我会非常感激
I'd appreciate it.
-当然  -谢谢你
- Of course. - Thank you.
她走了吗
Is she gone?
他们去追了吗
They going after her?
不
No.
我去
I am.
你有意见吗
You have a problem with that, too?
让她走吧
Let her go.
我为什么要那么做
Why would I do that?
她只想和她那伙人在一起
She just wants to be with her people.
你俩谈过了吗
You talked to her?
没
No.
你们谈过了
You did.
你知道她要走  不是吗
You knew she was leaving, didn't you?
她告诉我的
She told me.
你们还谈了些什么
What else did you two talk about, huh?
你把协议的事告诉她了
Did you tell her about the deal?
你把米琼恩的事告诉她了
Did you tell her about Michonne?
她知道了  不是吗
She knows, doesn't she?
准备好  一会儿出发
Be ready to roll in a few.
去哪儿
Where to?
我们不是去追那个姑娘  对吗
We're not going after that girl, are we?
如果是呢  有问题吗
What if we were? Is that a problem?
她情绪很激动
She was pretty shook up.
显然  她不想在这里待下去了
She definitely didn't want to be here.
听着  让她自生自灭吧  明白吗
Look, she's on her own, understood?
我们有别的事
We got something else.
一言难尽
It's sort of hard to explain.
五分钟后去卡车上
Just be at the truck in five.
-好的  -哪个姑娘
- Okay. - What girl?
安德莉亚翻墙走了
Andrea jumped the wall.
在你们眼皮底下吗  你们就放她走了吗
On your watch? And you let her go?
伙计  这些人一直在谈论她
Hey, man, these guys have been talking.
她是个麻烦
She's trouble.
也许问题不在她那里
Maybe she's not the issue.
她说了些很疯狂的话
She said some pretty crazy shit.
你知道为什么吗  因为她疯了
You know why? 'cause she's crazy.
我们好不容易留下  别搞砸了
Hey, don't screw this up for us.
-我只是警惕而已  -你们俩警惕去吧
- I'm just looking out. - For you two, maybe.
你什么意思
What the hell are you talking about?
我们在这里过得不错
We got a good thing here.
我可不想因为你被赶走
I don't want to get tossed out because of you.
这帮家伙紧张不安
These guys are on edge.
他们被那个疯牛仔还有
They've been attacked by that
一个拿刀的娘们给袭击了
crazy-ass cowboy and some chick with a sword.
马上要发生大事  你却在捣乱
Shit's going down and you're making waves.
我们只要乖乖守本分就好
We just have to get with the program.
我很守本分
I am.
那家伙不信任你
That guy doesn't trust you.
你别害了大家
Do not screw this up.
退后  哥们
Ease back, man.
不退怎样
Or what?
你又想当着我儿子的面羞辱我吗
You need to shame me in front of my boy again?
哥们  别挑那件事
Don't go there, man.
堂娜
Donna...
我只是碰巧在那儿
I just happened to be there.
-谁都有可能  -但偏偏不是别人
- It could have been anyone. - But it wasn't, was it?
-是你  -你们非要这时候吵吗
- It was you. - You want to do this now?
我早就想说了
A long time coming.
你俩聊吧
You guys catch up.
本  我们走
Come on, Ben.
没错  就是我  我救了她
Yeah, it was me. I saved her life.
在正确的地点  正确的时间
Right place, right time.
从那时起  她就像流浪狗一样死死跟着你了
And from that moment, she was glued to you like a lost puppy.
你成了她的黑马王子
Her knight in shining armor.
这让我觉得
It made me feel like...
-我也能救她  -我知道你可以
- I could have done it. - I know you could've.
-可她不知道  -她当然知道
- She didn't. - Of course she did.
她心里明白  她只是害怕而已
She knew that. She was just scared, that's all.
这不是你救还是我救的问题
This ain't got nothing to do with you or me.
你俩  快点儿
Yo, I said five.
走了  发动
Let's go. Fire it up.
这事儿还没完
We ain't done.
妈的
Shit.
这是什么
What is that?
宝贝  这是好东西
Jackpot, baby.
这是要搞人道毁灭吗
This some kind of extermination?
可以这么说吧  今天不杀行尸  香珀特
You could say that. No weeding out today, Shump.
-越多越好  -好的
- The more the merrier. - All right.
你们拿它们有用吗
You got a use for them?
宝贝  任何东西我们都有用
Honey, we got a use for everything.
这是为明天
This got something to do with
跟监狱那帮人的会议准备的吗
that meeting tomorrow? The one with the prison group?
恭喜你  答对了
Ho, ho, ho. Get that man a prize.
-你们要带行尸去  -艾伦  接着
- You're bringing biters? - Allen, heads up.
这真是太有才了
Okay, this is genius.
孩子  把车上的项圈拿来
Hey, kid, grab the collars out of the truck.
这不好吧
This ain't right.
哥们  今儿别给咱找麻烦
Didn't think we were gonna have any problems today, fella.
我不赞同拿人去喂行尸
I didn't think we'd be feeding people to biters.
你在乎什么  不过是些行尸
What do you care? They're rats.
太变态了
This is sick.
搭把手啊  泰尔西  你聋了吗
Hey, give me a hand here. Ty, you deaf?
我不干
I'm not doing this.
那儿有妇女和儿童
They got women and children.
你们不能这么做
You can't do this.
那随你便吧
Fine, suit yourself.
等我们回去  你自己跟总督说
We get back, you tell the governor.
他肯定让你滚蛋  让你们全滚蛋
He'll send you packing. Send you all packing.
-不必那样  该死  -放轻松
- There's no need for that. Dammit. - Relax.
之前我们都相互照应过来了
We looked out for each other.
大不了再来一次
We'll do it again.
如果你们一意孤行  我们就离开
We'll get out of your way if that's what you want.
你不能代表我们
You don't speak for us.
休想再让我的儿子出去送死
You're not sending my boy out there again.
-我要关照他  -就像关照堂娜那样吧
- I look out for him. - Like you looked out for Donna?
-泰尔西  -放开他
- Tyreese! - Leave him alone!
放开我
Get off me!
来啊
Do it.
放手啊
Go on!
别这样
Please.
放手
Go on!
你没事吧
You okay?
你们这是帮倒忙
You've all been very productive.
香珀特  把他们带回去
Shump, take 'em back to town.
他们只适合干针线活
Let 'em do some knitting.
安德利亚
Andrea.
跟我回去
Come back with me.
回伍德伯里
Come back to woodbury.
我们需要你
We need you.
大伙儿没你不行
We all need you.
那是你的家
That's your home now.
你的人民
Your people.
你的小镇
Your town.
你不能就这样撒手不管
You can't just leave 'em all behind.
安德利亚  拜托你回家吧
Please, Andrea, come home.
那随便你
Suit yourself.
回家时间到
Time to go home, huh?
安德利亚
Andrea.
找到她了吗
Did you find her?
没有
No luck.
刚得到消息  有人把坑里的行尸全烧了
Just got word. Someone barbecued the pit biters.
谁
Who?
两颗耗子屎搅坏一锅汤
Got a few shit stirrers in the bunch.
泰尔西和他姐姐
Tyreese and his sister.
让他们去仓库
Send them over to distro.
-四人组都去  -好
- Rest of the group, too. - All right.
我们需要行尸  再去找
We're still gonna need biters, so get some more.
好的
You got it.
抱歉让你们久等
Sorry to keep you waiting.
你找到她了吗
Did you find her?
没
No.
差点自己都没回来
Hardly made it back myself.
我明天再去找
I'll look again tomorrow.
听说你们在尸坑有点小争执
So I heard there was a little hang-up at the pits.
你跟瑞克有过节  我不在乎
You got a beef with Rick, that's fair enough.
但你不能把他的孩子们喂行尸
But you can't be feeding his kids to biters.
没人把谁喂行尸
No one's feeding anyone to biters.
我看到拖车了
Well, I saw the trailers.
那只是震慑战术  虚张声势
It's a scare tactic. It's a bluff.
我宁愿把他们吓跑
I'd rather scare his people into leaving us alone
也不愿交火
Than engaging in another fight.
我想拯救更多生命
I'm trying to save lives here.
-只是做做样子  -嗯
- They're just for show? - Uh-huh.
比起指在头上的枪  人们更害怕
You know, people are more afraid of a biter on a leash
被拴住的行尸
than a gun in their face.
很有效果
It's pretty effective.
你的手下为什么不直说
Then why didn't your man just say that?
因为
'Cause...
我们不会和生人
we don't discuss tactics with people
探讨战术策略
that we don't really know.
总督  听着
Governor, look.
我有时说话不经大脑
I shoot my mouth off sometimes,
但我们真的很想留下
but the truth is we want to stay.
我过激了  不会再发生
I saw red. It won't happen again.
很高兴你这么说
Well, I'm glad to hear it.
汽油你在哪找的
Where did you get the gasoline?
什么
Come again?
没什么
Doesn't matter.
她死了吗
Is she dead?
但愿没有
I hope not.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
从未如此之好
Never been better.
尸坑被毁真可惜
It's a real shame about the pits.
你也听说了
You heard about that, huh?
希望你能找出是谁做的
I hope you find out who did it.
我已经知道了
Already have.